<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Mastodon Home Timeline</title><link>https://mastodon.social</link><description>RSS feed for the Mastodon Home timeline</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:26:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chuck Darwin</title><link>https://c.im/@cdarwin/113675792642425057</link><description>“Luigi mentioned you in his manifesto. That people should listen to you. Will you come on our show, or talk to our reporter and tell them that you condemn murder!?”It’s not often that my work gets a killer five-star review from an actual killer. And thus, my phone has been ringing off the hook which is bad news because my phone doesn’t have a hook. Emails are pouring in. Text messages. Requests from many in the media. Hmmm. Do I condemn murder? &lt;br/&gt;That’s an odd question. In Fahrenheit 9/11, I condemned the murder of hundreds of thousands of innocent Iraqi people and the senseless murder of our own American soldiers at the hands of our American government. In Bowling for Columbine, I condemned the murder of 50,000 Americans every year at the hands of our gun industry and our politicians who do nothing to stop it.In my 35 years as a filmmaker, have I said or done anything that has implied I condone murder? As a teenager during the Vietnam War, I was required to register for the draft at the local draft board. &lt;br/&gt;There was a box on the form asking me if I had a problem with killing Vietnamese people. Actually, it just asked me to check the box if I was going to file for Conscientious Objector status &lt;br/&gt;— meaning, if given the opportunity, would I swear that I would never kill a Vietnamese person. I checked the box. Throughout my adult life, I have repeatedly stated that I’m a pacifist. In fact, I have never struck another human in my life. 👉Here’s a sad statistic for you: In the United States, we have a whopping 1.4 million people employed with the job of DENYING HEALTH CARE, &lt;br/&gt;vs only 1 million doctors in the entire country! That’s all you need to know about America. We pay more people to deny care than to give it. 1 million doctors to give care, 1.4 million brutes in cubicles doing their best to stop doctors from giving that care. If the purpose of “health care” is to keep people alive, then what is the purpose of DENYING PEOPLE HEALTH CARE? Other than to kill them? I definitely condemn that kind of murder. And in fact, I already did. In 2007, I made a film &lt;br/&gt;– SICKO &lt;br/&gt;– about America’s bloodthirsty, profit-driven and murderous health insurance system. It was nominated for an Oscar. It’s the second-largest grossing film of my career (after Fahrenheit 9/11). And over the past 15 years, millions upon millions of people have watched it including, apparently, Luigi Mangione.After the killing of the CEO of United HealthCare, &lt;br/&gt;the largest of these billion dollar insurance companies, &lt;br/&gt;there was an immediate OUTPOURING of anger toward the health insurance industry. Some people have stepped forward to condemn this anger. I am not one of them. The anger is 1000% justified. It is long overdue for the media to cover it. It is not new. It has been boiling. And I’m not going to tamp it down or ask people to shut up. I want to pour gasoline on that anger. Because this anger is not about the killing of a CEO. If everyone who was angry was ready to kill the CEOs, &lt;br/&gt;the CEOs would already be dead. That is not what this reaction is about. It is about the mass death and misery &lt;br/&gt;— the physical pain, the mental abuse, the medical debt, the bankruptcies in the face of denied claims and denied care and bottomless deductibles on top of ballooning premiums &lt;br/&gt;— that this “health care” industry has levied against the American people for decades. With no one standing in their way! Just a government &lt;br/&gt;— two broken parties &lt;br/&gt;— enabling this INDUSTRY’s theft and, yes, murder-- Michael Moore&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.michaelmoore.com/p/a-manifesto-against-for-profit-health" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;michaelmoore.com/p/a-manifesto&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;-against-for-profit-health&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113682415286998738</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:53:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Boris Barbour</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@BorisBarbour/113686721587167911</link><description>Shameful prosecution.&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/dec/20/yolanda-borucki-ashley-griffith-computer-hacking-charge-not-guilty-ntwnfb" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;theguardian.com/australia-news&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;/2024/dec/20/yolanda-borucki-ashley-griffith-computer-hacking-charge-not-guilty-ntwnfb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113686721587167911</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 19:08:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earl K. Miller</title><link>https://fediscience.org/@ekmiller/113687016787041186</link><description>Traveling waves are the next frontier.&lt;br/&gt;Traveling waves enhance hippocampal-parahippocampal couplings in human episodic and working memory&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2024.12.10.627735v1.abstract" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;24.12.10.627735v1.abstract&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://fediscience.org/tags/neuroscience" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;neuroscience&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113687016900363394</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 20:23:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Le Chep</title><link>https://piaille.fr/@c_chep/113687067770841226</link><description>&lt;span class="h-card" translate="no"&gt;&lt;a class="u-url mention" href="https://mamot.fr/@CyrilBrulebois" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;@&lt;span&gt;CyrilBrulebois&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="h-card" translate="no"&gt;&lt;a class="u-url mention" href="https://climatejustice.social/@MurmeltHier" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;@&lt;span&gt;MurmeltHier&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="h-card" translate="no"&gt;&lt;a class="u-url mention" href="https://chaos.social/@zhenech" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;@&lt;span&gt;zhenech&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; there's even a list of hairdresser salons with puns in their names on a government site &lt;a href="https://www.data.gouv.fr/fr/datasets/coordonnees-des-enseignes-de-coiffure-comportant-des-jeux-de-mots-cocasses-dans-leur-appellation/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;data.gouv.fr/fr/datasets/coord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;onnees-des-enseignes-de-coiffure-comportant-des-jeux-de-mots-cocasses-dans-leur-appellation/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113687932461475524</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:16:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>David Chisnall (*Now with 50% more sarcasm!*)</title><link>https://infosec.exchange/@david_chisnall/113690087142854474</link><description>I finally turned off GitHub Copilot yesterday. I’ve been using it for about a year on the ‘free for open-source maintainers’ tier. I was skeptical but didn’t want to dismiss it without a fair trial.It has cost me more time than it has saved. It lets me type faster, which has been useful when writing tests where I’m testing a variety of permutations of an API to check error handling for all of the conditions.I can recall three places where it has introduced bugs that took me more time to to debug than the total time saving:The first was something that initially impressed me. I pasted the prose description of how to communicate with an Ethernet MAC into a comment and then wrote some method prototypes. It autocompleted the bodies. All very plausible looking. Only it managed to flip a bit in the MDIO read and write register commands.  MDIO is basically a multiplexing system. You have two device registers exposed, one sets the command (read or write a specific internal register) and the other is the value. It got the read and write the wrong way around, so when I thought I was writing a value, I was actually reading. When I thought I was reading, I was actually seeing the value in the last register I thought I had written. It took two of us over a day to debug this. The fix was simple, but the bug was in the middle of correct-looking code. If I’d manually transcribed the command from the data sheet, I would not have got this wrong because I’d have triple checked it.Another case it had inverted the condition in an if statement inside an error-handling path. The error handling was a rare case and was asymmetric. Hitting the if case when you wanted the else case was okay but the converse was not. Lots of debugging. I learned from this to read the generated code more carefully, but that increased cognitive load and eliminated most of the benefit. Typing code is not the bottleneck and if I have to think about what I want and then read carefully to check it really is what I want, I am slower.Most recently, I was writing a simple binary search and insertion-deletion operations for a sorted array. I assumed that this was something that had hundreds of examples in the training data and so would be fine. It had all sorts of corner-case bugs. I eventually gave up fixing them and rewrote the code from scratch.Last week I did some work on a remote machine where I hadn’t set up Copilot and I felt much more productive. Autocomplete was either correct or not present, so I was spending more time thinking about what to write. I don’t entirely trust this kind of subjective judgement, but it was a data point. Around the same time I wrote some code without clangd set up and that &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; hurt. It turns out I really rely on AST-aware completion to explore APIs. I had to look up more things in the documentation. Copilot was never good for this because it would just bullshit APIs, so something showing up in autocomplete didn’t mean it was real. This would be improved by using a feedback system to require autocomplete outputs to type check, but then they would take much longer to create (probably at least a 10x increase in LLM compute time) and wouldn’t complete fragments, so I don’t see a good path to being able to do this without tight coupling to the LSP server and possibly not even then.Yesterday I was writing bits of the CHERIoT Programmers’ Guide and it kept autocompleting text in a different writing style, some of which was obviously plagiarised (when I’m describing precisely how to implement a specific, and not very common, lock type with a futex and the autocomplete is a paragraph of text with a lot of detail, I’m confident you don’t have more than one or two examples of that in the training set). It was distracting and annoying. I wrote much faster after turning it off.So, after giving it a fair try, I have concluded that it is both a net decrease in productivity and probably an increase in legal liability.Discussions I am not interested in having:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You are holding it wrong. Using Copilot with this magic config setting / prompt tweak makes it better. At its absolute best, it was a small productivity increase, if it needs more effort to use, that will be offset.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This other LLM is &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better. I don’t care. The costs of the bullshitting far outweighed the benefits when it worked, to be better it would have to &lt;em&gt;not bullshit&lt;/em&gt;, and that’s not something LLMs can do.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It’s great for boilerplate! No. APIs that require every user to write the same code &lt;em&gt;are broken&lt;/em&gt;. Fix them, don’t fill the world with more code using them that will need fixing when the APIs change.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don’t use LLMs for autocomplete, use them for dialogues about the code. Tried that. It’s worse than a rubber duck, which at least knows to stay silent when it doesn’t know what it’s talking about.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;The one place Copilot was vaguely useful was hinting at missing abstractions (if it can autocomplete big chunks then my APIs required too much boilerplate and needed better abstractions). The place I thought it might be useful was spotting inconsistent API names and parameter orders but it was actually very bad at this (presumably because of the way it tokenises identifiers?). With a load of examples with consistent names, it would suggest things that didn't match the convention. After using three APIs that all passed the same parameters in the same order, it would suggest flipping the order for the fourth.&lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://infosec.exchange/tags/GitHubCopilot" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;GitHubCopilot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://infosec.exchange/tags/CHERIoT" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;CHERIoT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113690527970573288</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 11:16:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Boris Barbour</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@BorisBarbour/113690712600474733</link><description>Marina Hyde with the righteous anger on the continuing miscarriage of justice in the Post Office scandal. The scales of justice in the UK are staggeringly tilted in favour of "establishment" perpetrators. Hillsborough and Chris Day also spring to mind. Heads absolutely should roll and be seen to roll.&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2024/dec/20/post-office-inquiry-tv-show-subpostmasters-britain" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;theguardian.com/commentisfree/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;2024/dec/20/post-office-inquiry-tv-show-subpostmasters-britain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113690712600474733</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 12:03:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Boris Barbour</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@BorisBarbour/113690718593268813</link><description>&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/113/690/718/367/184/530/original/acb85508966ee0cb.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/113/690/718/367/184/530/original/acb85508966ee0cb.png" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113690718593268813</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 12:04:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Manlio De Domenico</title><link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@manlius/113691472848625910</link><description>I have seen several profiles featuring a link to Linktree, and it piqued my curiosity.It indeed seems like a convenient way to consolidate all our profiles and important links in one place. So... here is mine: &lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/manlius" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=""&gt;linktr.ee/manlius&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/113/691/472/967/903/929/original/b97cc9f7bf02bd66.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/113/691/472/967/903/929/original/b97cc9f7bf02bd66.jpg" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113691473013820957</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:16:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Manlio De Domenico</title><link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@manlius/113691502474274853</link><description>This year edition, the 10th, of the Mediterranean School of Complex Networks will be in Ortigia, a small Island near Siracusa, in my beloved birthplace, Sicily.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/1ecpwfqBZMM" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=""&gt;youtu.be/1ecpwfqBZMM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Apply here: &lt;a href="https://mediterraneanschoolcomplex.net/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;mediterraneanschoolcomplex.net&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;See you there in July 2025 to do network science together!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113691502582956210</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:24:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Allan Barte</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@AllanBarte/113686367347261918</link><description>Les aventures de Macron : aujourd'hui, Macron promène sa suffisance, son mépris et son racisme à Mayotte.Pour soutenir la lutte dessinée :&lt;br/&gt;▶️ &lt;a href="https://ko-fi.com/allanbarte" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=""&gt;ko-fi.com/allanbarte&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;▶️ Source : &lt;a href="https://www.leparisien.fr/politique/mayotte-macron-veut-rebatir-avec-de-nouveaux-criteres-et-renforcer-la-lutte-contre-limmigration-clandestine-19-12-2024-VMDBXI22DBFYVILYBG5RFECRRM.php" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;leparisien.fr/politique/mayott&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;e-macron-veut-rebatir-avec-de-nouveaux-criteres-et-renforcer-la-lutte-contre-limmigration-clandestine-19-12-2024-VMDBXI22DBFYVILYBG5RFECRRM.php&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/113/686/361/443/147/784/original/b1ae606dae035608.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/113/686/361/443/147/784/original/b1ae606dae035608.jpg" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113691726235160312</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:21:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Boris Barbour</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@BorisBarbour/113692347238696672</link><description>&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/20/cory-doctorow-radicalized-novella-healthcare-ceo-killing" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;theguardian.com/us-news/2024/d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;ec/20/cory-doctorow-radicalized-novella-healthcare-ceo-killing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113692347238696672</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 18:59:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chris Smart, ve3rwj</title><link>https://mastodon.radio/@VE3RWJ/113682071820570507</link><description>This is big!&lt;br/&gt;The Ugly &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.radio/tags/Truth" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;Truth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; About &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.radio/tags/Spotify" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;Spotify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is Finally Revealed. A year-long &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.radio/tags/investigation" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;investigation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by an independent journalist is very alarming!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.honest-broker.com/p/the-ugly-truth-about-spotify-is-finally?utm_source=post-email-title&amp;amp;publication_id=296132&amp;amp;post_id=153380958&amp;amp;utm_campaign=email-post-title&amp;amp;isFreemail=false&amp;amp;r=y7b5m&amp;amp;triedRedirect=true&amp;amp;utm_medium=email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;honest-broker.com/p/the-ugly-t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;ruth-about-spotify-is-finally?utm_source=post-email-title&amp;amp;publication_id=296132&amp;amp;post_id=153380958&amp;amp;utm_campaign=email-post-title&amp;amp;isFreemail=false&amp;amp;r=y7b5m&amp;amp;triedRedirect=true&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.radio/tags/music" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;music&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.radio/tags/streaming" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;streaming&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.radio/tags/payola" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;payola&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.radio/tags/TedGioia" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;TedGioia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113692394064039196</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 19:10:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jan Wildeboer 😷:krulorange:</title><link>https://social.wildeboer.net/@jwildeboer/113692568301733763</link><description>German public broadcaster BR published a 3 part series called &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://social.wildeboer.net/tags/DirtyLittleSecrets" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;DirtyLittleSecrets&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on how &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://social.wildeboer.net/tags/Spotify" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;Spotify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses fake artists to make more money. How the record labels were part of this. And how real artists are left behind. In May 2023. So I am a little surprised how this suddenly becomes a new story. Trailer: &lt;a href="https://www.ardmediathek.de/video/Y3JpZDovL2JyLmRlL2Jyb2FkY2FzdFNjaGVkdWxlU2xvdC81M2ZhOTJjYy1jNmFkLTQ5MGYtOGVjMi1hYWNkNzQzOGU3ZDg" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;ardmediathek.de/video/Y3JpZDov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;L2JyLmRlL2Jyb2FkY2FzdFNjaGVkdWxlU2xvdC81M2ZhOTJjYy1jNmFkLTQ5MGYtOGVjMi1hYWNkNzQzOGU3ZDg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113692725019144454</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 20:35:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TheMetaNews</title><link>https://social.sciences.re/@TheMetaNews/113690857207889940</link><description>Hello Mastodon, &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://social.sciences.re/tags/HelloESR" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;HelloESR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; !On était sur BS depuis quelques temps mais notre départ définitif de X nous a décidé à tenter l'aventure sur Mastodon également !On postera ici au sujet de nos derniers articles, sur lesquels on sera très heureux·ses de lire vos réactions, donc n'hésitez pas à commenter et à partager.Et bien évidemment les réseaux sociaux peuvent être un bon outil de veille pour nous journalistes, donc n'hésitez pas à nous identifier sur des infos/questions que vous jugez importantes.À très bientôt,&lt;br/&gt;L'équipe de TMN</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113696178065106068</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 11:13:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anne Applebaum</title><link>https://journa.host/@anneapplebaum/113695841178236147</link><description>Did Musk tank a spending bill because it would have harmed his business in China? &lt;br/&gt;From The American Prospect &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://prospect.org/politics/2024-12-20-government-shutting-down-elon-musk-factories-china/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;prospect.org/politics/2024-12-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;20-government-shutting-down-elon-musk-factories-china/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/113/695/842/259/655/211/original/07f160ef1451311e.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/113/695/842/259/655/211/original/07f160ef1451311e.jpg" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113696684346421338</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 13:22:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vincenzo Marra</title><link>https://mstdn.social/@enzomarra/113696982404643510</link><description>Applications to the 2025 Paris Neuro Course are now open. Deadline on the 1st of February. The course will run 14-27 May 2025.parisneuro.ovh</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113696997224251754</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 14:41:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pтiт Poиeч de Fiиdцs</title><link>https://piaille.fr/@0xdefec7edcafe/113697272529924356</link><description>C'est quand tu deviens prof que tu découvres que LaTeX a un mode exam:\documentclass[12pt,a4paper]{exam}</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113697657387296699</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 17:29:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spencer LaVere Smith</title><link>https://neuromatch.social/@sls/113698062497154782</link><description>I'm excited that Pacific Optica is releasing their new scan optics.  &lt;a href="https://pacificoptica.com/ventana/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=""&gt;pacificoptica.com/ventana/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; For those of you who know two-photon imaging well, check out the specs on the link. These optics are unprecedented. They're easy to integrate into a rig (using Thorlabs SM2 and SM3 threads) and they provide a way bigger diffraction-limited imaging field-of-view. No more vignetting due to the scan engine.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/113/698/062/541/880/580/original/2ee76ae12d1bfdf0.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/113/698/062/541/880/580/original/2ee76ae12d1bfdf0.png" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113698062620791039</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 19:12:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Allan Barte</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@AllanBarte/113697418490561334</link><description>Gouvernement Bayrou : les derniers réglages &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/Rebsamen" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;Rebsamen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Pour soutenir la lutte dessinée :&lt;br/&gt;▶️ &lt;a href="https://ko-fi.com/allanbarte" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=""&gt;ko-fi.com/allanbarte&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/113/697/406/285/891/342/original/9e8ca023814fae77.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/113/697/406/285/891/342/original/9e8ca023814fae77.jpg" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113698162346696651</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 19:37:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pтiт Poиeч de Fiиdцs</title><link>https://piaille.fr/@0xdefec7edcafe/113687205621039960</link><description>CISA ( Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency) i.e. l'agence américaine de cyberdéfense, recommande d'éviter le plus possible le protocole SMS en particulier pour les authentifications 2 facteurs (2FA) &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/sites/default/files/2024-12/guidance-mobile-communications-best-practices.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;cisa.gov/sites/default/files/2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;024-12/guidance-mobile-communications-best-practices.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113698473823190335</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 20:57:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>