<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Mastodon Home Timeline</title><link>https://mastodon.social</link><description>RSS feed for the Mastodon Home timeline</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 11:13:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hilda Bastian</title><link>https://mastodon.online/@hildabast/110547504083903588</link><description>Well, it's done! I've now left Substack, and will delete the newsletter when subscriber views to my farewell post trickle out.My newsletter, Living With Evidence, is now at WordPress. (Link to subscribe in bio.)My first post is up now:A Fresh Start!&lt;a href="https://hildabastian.wordpress.com/2023/06/15/a-fresh-start/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;hildabastian.wordpress.com/202&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;3/06/15/a-fresh-start/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The post's pic is this lavender from my garden. That's because it was transplanted as a seedling from a friend's house, and I'm hoping my digital transplant is as successful!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/110/547/504/154/524/898/original/376982b29089f478.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/110/547/504/154/524/898/original/376982b29089f478.jpg" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110548133626085319</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 12:04:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cian O’Donnell</title><link>https://mstdn.science/@cian/110541566864740632</link><description>Neural activity has dynamics on ms-second timescales, but organism behaviour during learning is over seconds-mins. Existing plasticity models dont bridge this gap.I wrote a review arguing for adding nonlinear slow-timescale variables to plasticity rules: &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.07801" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=""&gt;arxiv.org/abs/2306.07801&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110548202563368889</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 12:21:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof. Mayank R Mehta, UCLA</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@Learning/110549005623411300</link><description>Imagine a free, informal block party. Then, a bully walks in, injects himself in all conversations, spreads misinformation, fires people and asks for a monthly $8 fee. That's what M#$k did and gained a whopping 100million+ followers within a year. Do you support this?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/110/549/004/857/438/492/original/a25766a02230740b.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/110/549/004/857/438/492/original/a25766a02230740b.png" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110549005623411300</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 15:45:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pierre-Simon Laplace</title><link>https://mstdn.science/@LearnBayesStats/110549140647779389</link><description>episode 84 with &lt;span class="h-card"&gt;&lt;a class="u-url mention" href="https://neuromatch.social/@kordinglab" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;@&lt;span&gt;kordinglab&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is out! 🥳&lt;br/&gt;We return to one of our favourite topics: the brain 🧠&amp;amp; what it does.&lt;br/&gt;We talk about &lt;br/&gt;- causal inference&lt;br/&gt;- the credit assignment problem in &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mstdn.science/tags/neuroscience" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;neuroscience&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- and more &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mstdn.science/tags/psychology" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;psychology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; neuroscience &lt;br/&gt;Tune in here: &lt;a href="https://learnbayesstats.com/episode/84-causality-neuroscience-psychology-konrad-kording/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;learnbayesstats.com/episode/84&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;-causality-neuroscience-psychology-konrad-kording/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110549521289659358</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 17:57:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sainsbury Wellcome Centre</title><link>https://neuromatch.social/@SWC_Neuro/110548907905177310</link><description>We are delighted to announce that Tim Behrens (&lt;span class="h-card"&gt;&lt;a class="u-url mention" href="https://fediscience.org/@behrenstimb" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;@&lt;span&gt;behrenstimb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) has joined SWC as a Group Leader. The Behrens Lab will strive to understand the neural mechanisms that support flexible goal-directed behaviour. In doing so, the team hope to build new bridges between human and animal neuroscience, between biological and artificial intelligence, and new methods for integrating across scales of neural activity.Find out more: &lt;a href="https://www.sainsburywellcome.org/web/research-news/tim-behrens-joins-swc-group-leader" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;sainsburywellcome.org/web/rese&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;arch-news/tim-behrens-joins-swc-group-leader&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/110/548/907/927/940/794/original/4530d7cf3cf7abdb.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/110/548/907/927/940/794/original/4530d7cf3cf7abdb.png" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110549667949800554</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 18:34:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Michele Banks</title><link>https://chaos.social/@artologica/110542705516476646</link><description>Very satisfying. Gonna put this one in the NIH exhibition &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://chaos.social/tags/art" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;art&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://chaos.social/tags/painting" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;painting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://chaos.social/tags/inkpainting" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;inkpainting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://chaos.social/tags/sciart" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;sciart&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/110/542/705/580/446/637/original/11f83e5b99db948b.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/110/542/705/580/446/637/original/11f83e5b99db948b.jpg" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110550259915579704</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 21:04:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Boris Barbour</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@BorisBarbour/110552570112768488</link><description>We knew it, but what a mad bunch of supporters Johnson collected and rewarded using taxpayers money with spectacularly unmerited positions in the Lord's.&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2023/jun/15/boris-johnson-allies-fury-partygate-report" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;theguardian.com/politics/2023/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;jun/15/boris-johnson-allies-fury-partygate-report&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110552570112768488</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 06:52:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>gbhnews</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@gbhnews/110548581726091393</link><description>🌞 Good morning &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/fediverse" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;fediverse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;! This is GBH News from &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/Boston" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;Boston&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It's 64F at Logan Airport and visibility is 10 miles. Defendants in the disturbing case of body parts from donated cadavers being sold from the Harvard Medical School morgue appeared in court to face charges yesterday. No more rides to Hel on buss 666 in Poland; the bus operator is changing the bus's route number. &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/transit" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;transit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; GLAAD has rated Twitter at the bottom when it comes to protecting &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/LGBTQ" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;LGBTQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; people from harassment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110552613933406950</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 07:03:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Boris Barbour</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@BorisBarbour/110552727427362845</link><description>Interesting limits to this sum. A small tear in the matrix...&lt;a href="https://pubpeer.com/publications/E290C3EF2056A49A3505EE533F3C39#4" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;pubpeer.com/publications/E290C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;3EF2056A49A3505EE533F3C39#4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/110/550/573/676/367/793/original/29e8a96b129e7670.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/110/550/573/676/367/793/original/29e8a96b129e7670.png" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110552727427362845</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 07:32:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Romain Brette</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@romainbrette/110552771888299991</link><description>Why large language models or deep nets are not conscious:&lt;a href="http://romainbrette.fr/notes-on-consciousness-xi-why-large-language-models-are-not-conscious/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;http://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;romainbrette.fr/notes-on-consc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;iousness-xi-why-large-language-models-are-not-conscious/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;(Where I argue that we don't know what consciousness is exactly, but we do have an idea of what consciousness is not)</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110552771888299991</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 07:43:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Justin Schuh</title><link>https://infosec.exchange/@jschuh/110551298514321829</link><description>The Difference Between How Trump, Biden, Pence, and Clinton Mishandled Classified InformationI should first state where I’m coming from (because &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://infosec.exchange/tags/IANAL" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;IANAL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). I served in the US intelligence community from 1996-2004, first as an enlisted Marine, and then as a federal employee at NSA and later CIA. I worked on watchfloors and did ops, but most of that career was spent managing and/or securing classified systems. I was trained at the Fort Washington¹ facility in qualifying SCIFs², had my classified courier card for years, and in my time saw a few classified mishandling cases up close.Next is a bit of background on how classified information handling works. In the 99.99% case, classified docs are only ever handled in SCIFs (which have fence-lines and armed guards). Printed documents are marked with their classification level, and when not in use everything is locked in a properly rated safe, managed with access logs. Classified computer systems are rated to the maximum level of classified allowed, and also secured when not in use. Systems at different classification levels are air-gapped to prevent leakage (technically it’s more complicated, but accurate for this discussion).The last bit of background is the legal framework for classified document handling. There actually is no law defining classified information or handling processes. Rather, there’s the 1917 Espionage Act³, plus 100 years of legal precedent and executive orders (most recently EO 13526⁴). The Espionage Act refers to a very broad category of “information respecting the national defense” and makes illegal the dissemination of this information through either “willful intent” or “gross negligence.”The key point is that the law applies to a broad category of information, and the EOs build a framework for identifying such information and how to securely handle it. This is also the main basis that the courts use to delineate violations of the law, which is why classified mishandling is prosecuted under the Espionage Act.With all of that out of the way, it’s time to look at each of these cases of classified mishandling. I’ll start with Clinton’s case first, because it’s the weirdest, in that it only barely involves classified data handling. That might seem confusing given all the press coverage in 2016, but the most accurate description of what Clinton did is that she forwarded emails from her official DoS (Department of State) email account to a personal account. The critical thing here is that because her DoS account was on a FOUO (For Official Use Only⁵) system, directly connected to the public Internet, those emails never should have contained any classified information. FOUO systems may contain sensitive information, but are explicitly not for handling classified information.Accepting that, sometimes classified information leaks to a FOUO system. This tends to happen one of two ways, the first of which is usually in preparing briefings/reports for a lower classification level. It’s common to pull some of that information from classified documents, declassify as needed, and then transfer that to a lower classification system. Sometimes mistakes are made in this process and (now invalid) classification markings are left in the downgraded document. That explains the classification markings found in a few of Clinton’s emails⁶.Classified information can also leak without being marked, if the substance of discussion simply includes information that would be considered classified. This is why it was reported that Clinton had 2,100 classified email threads⁷. Because, all of her emails were sent to the classification authorities at all of the intelligence agencies, and they reviewed everything, flagging anything they would have viewed as classified. FWIW, I doubt that any senior national security official’s FOUO inbox would make it through this process without coming away similarly flagged (but that's its own very long discussion).With that context, here’s the first critical thing to understand about Clinton’s emails: The classified information leak was independent of her forwarding her official email to her personal email address. This is because any classified information she received was already leaked on the FOUO systems that the emails were coming from. So, the classified mishandling situation is the same regardless of whether Clinton’s email had remained on the FOUO DoS server or on a machine in Clinton’s basement. Neither are authorized for handling classified information.So, then what was wrong with Clinton forwarding her FOUO emails to a personal address? Mainly it comes down to the government’s obligations regarding records retention and the mandatory security baseline for the systems they manage. Those are both extremely good reasons for why Clinton shouldn’t have forwarded her emails, but they don’t really have anything to do with classified information handling.And to be fair to Clinton, since she was using a FOUO system, she had a reasonable expectation that she wasn’t receiving any emails containing classified information. So, unless she personally introduced the classified information into the discussions that got retroactively flagged, it’s entirely possible that she never even mishandled classified herself. Rather, she may have simply had additional copies of emails that had already leaked to FOUO systems. (FWIW, I don’t expect to ever find out the answer to this.)This gets to the legal repercussions of what Clinton did. Once again, IANAL, but I did see cases of similar infractions. And as long as the offending party cooperated, there was very little in the way of repercussions. About the worst case would be junior enlisted getting slapped with non-judicial punishment⁸ because their commander wanted to make an example of them. But outside of that, pretty much anyone else in the same situation would just be told to stop, or at worst get a minor slap on the wrist.Either way, I cannot imagine what grounds someone could even be prosecuted over if they're simply forwarding emails from a FOUO account, to their personal account, for the purposes of accessing their email from another device. Moreover, the scope and depth of the Clinton investigation would normally have been reserved for someone stealing actual marked classified information or otherwise bridging classification levels between systems. Clinton genuinely received more scrutiny and greater repercussions than pretty much anyone else in her situation would have. None of this is to say that what Clinton did was a good thing, but it genuinely was far less than it's usually made out to be.Now, on to Biden and Pence, which are nearly identical cases of classified mishandling. Remember several paragraphs back about the 99.99% case? Well, that’s not the White House, because that place is just weird. It has a mess of spaces cleared for handling classified, and uncleared people endlessly circulating about—some of whom literally live there! The whole thing is a security nightmare, and they should ban printed classified just as a precautionary measure.That’s why I’m not surprised that Biden and Pence wound up with marked classified papers mixed in with their other documents. TBH I’m surprised it doesn’t happen more often. But that sort of thing is also why the statute sets the bar at “willfully” or “negligent.” Both Biden and Pence did exactly the right thing in notifying the appropriate custodian of the mistake, turning over everything, and complying fully with investigations. It was all by the book, and no one would ever be charged for something like this.Finally, we get to Trump. His case is highly unusual, but not at all complicated. The indictment⁹ provides mounds of evidence that he “willfully” took large quantities of classified material with him when he left the White House. After NARA (National Archives and Records Administration) contacted him about returning the missing classified material, he chose to lie, evade, and then turn over only some of the stolen documents. Eventually the FBI had to raid Mar-a-Lago to recover 300+ additional classified documents, and it’s still unclear whether everything has been recovered.The whole point here is that the Trump case is genuinely unprecedented in just how crazy it is. The volume and scope of the theft puts it in league with espionage cases that land people in prison for decades. Even worse, the whole crime is documented with recordings, corroborating witnesses, and pretty much everything a prosecutor could dream of. While I'm at it I should also quickly knock out some of the more common attempts I’ve seen to dismiss the criminality of Trump’s situation, so here goes: Are the classified documents in fact Trump’s property? No. The Presidential Records Act is entirely clear on this¹⁰.Could Trump have declassified these documents already as president? No. EO 13526 sets out the classification process, and if he wanted to expand it to include psychic declassification he had to write a superseding EO laying out such a process.Does it matter that Trump doesn’t appear to be an agent of a foreign power? No. Just ask Petraeus¹¹ or Schulte¹²; you break the law when you willfully take the information and risk dissemination to those not cleared for access.Does it matter that Trump stored the information in a locked room? Accepting that a resort with random people ambling about is laughably unsafe, the fact is that there are clear regulations for storage and transport of classified material, and Trump was so far outside the bounds of those that the tiny measures he took are immaterial.TL;DR: Literally anyone else who did what Trump did would already be sitting in federal prison for at least a decade. Trump is getting an unheard of level of special treatment—entirely to his own benefit! There’s simply no comparison to what Clinton, Biden, or Pence did. The most appropriate comparisons for Trump’s case all involve people currently serving long federal prison sentences… or people who already died in prison.&lt;br/&gt;_&lt;br/&gt;¹ &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interagency_Training_Center" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;ncy_Training_Center&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;² &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sensitive_compartmented_information_facility" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sensitiv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;e_compartmented_information_facility&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;³ &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Espionage_Act_of_1917" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Espionag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;e_Act_of_1917&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;⁴ &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Executive_Order_13526" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Executiv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;e_Order_13526&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;⁵ &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/For_Official_Use_Only" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/For_Offi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;cial_Use_Only&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;⁶ &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/blogs/under-the-radar/2016/07/hillary-clinton-classified-emails-error-225194" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;politico.com/blogs/under-the-r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;adar/2016/07/hillary-clinton-classified-emails-error-225194&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;⁷ &lt;a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/politics/articles/2016-02-29/state-dept-wins-dispute-over-clinton-email-on-north-korea" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;usnews.com/news/politics/artic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;les/2016-02-29/state-dept-wins-dispute-over-clinton-email-on-north-korea&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;⁸ &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-judicial_punishment" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-judi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;cial_punishment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;⁹ &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/storage/US_v_Trump-Nauta_23-80101.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;justice.gov/storage/US_v_Trump&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;-Nauta_23-80101.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;¹⁰ &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Presidential_Records_Act" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Presiden&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;tial_Records_Act&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;¹¹ &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Petraeus#Criminal_charges_and_probation" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Pe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;traeus#Criminal_charges_and_probation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;¹² &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joshua_Schulte" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joshua_S&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;chulte&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110553475775422755</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 10:42:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Steve Crawford</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@crawfordsm/110548394727189416</link><description>NASA has gone beyond the requirements of the OSTP memo to not only include full open access to data and publications at the time of publication, but also scientific software developed as part of the project and needed to validate the scientific results</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110553535124215142</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 10:57:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Marquis Lafayette</title><link>https://c.im/@RenegadeSci/110552347300467500</link><description>Elon Musk's social media site bans political ads supporting family planning and reproductive health.  &lt;a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/rachel-hunt-north-carolina-twitter-video-abortion_n_648b4257e4b0756ff8631dec" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;huffpost.com/entry/rachel-hunt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;-north-carolina-twitter-video-abortion_n_648b4257e4b0756ff8631dec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110553603091342915</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 11:15:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Matteo Carandini</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@MatteoCarandini/110554109509680842</link><description>Delighted to announce the 2023 UCL Neuropixels Course. &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/Neuropixels" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;Neuropixels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  probes are transforming &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/neuroscience" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;neuroscience&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This free online course trains scientists to use them and process their output. Day 1 (17 October 2023) covers the basics. Day 2 (18 October 2023) does a deep dive into 4 hot topics: the 2.0 release, the latest Kilosort, chronic recording implants, and software to track the same neurons across days.For more info and to register:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ucl.ac.uk/neuropixels/training/2023-neuropixels-course" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;ucl.ac.uk/neuropixels/training&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;/2023-neuropixels-course&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/110/554/097/603/198/837/original/f5e90a55bb689cba.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/110/554/097/603/198/837/original/f5e90a55bb689cba.png" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110554109509680842</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 13:23:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Philip N Cohen</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@philipncohen/110553945465428729</link><description>&lt;span class="h-card"&gt;&lt;a class="u-url mention" href="https://mastodon.social/@BorisBarbour"&gt;@&lt;span&gt;BorisBarbour&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="h-card"&gt;&lt;a class="u-url mention" href="https://mastodon.social/@richvn"&gt;@&lt;span&gt;richvn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; No Paper, No Press Release</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110554898805696669</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 16:44:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ஐஇΛɔϛƐɐ‾ᄅ³ᄅᄅ™</title><link>https://universeodon.com/@JazzAficionado/110554248162782490</link><description>&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/110/554/248/195/129/661/original/d73d520838322d7b.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/110/554/248/195/129/661/original/d73d520838322d7b.png" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110554911285241795</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 16:47:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earl K. Miller</title><link>https://fediscience.org/@ekmiller/110555282898431881</link><description>Rules in subspace.  Very cool.Ensembles code for associative learning in the primate lateral prefrontal cortex&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2023.112449" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2023.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;112449&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110555282989702815</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 18:22:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earl K. Miller</title><link>https://fediscience.org/@ekmiller/110555291753693134</link><description>The impact of the human thalamus on brain-wide information processing&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41583-023-00701-0" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;nature.com/articles/s41583-023&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;-00701-0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110555291997735918</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 18:24:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Richard Van Noorden</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@richvn/110555299559932039</link><description>&lt;span class="h-card"&gt;&lt;a class="u-url mention" href="https://mastodon.social/@philipncohen"&gt;@&lt;span&gt;philipncohen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="h-card"&gt;&lt;a class="u-url mention" href="https://mastodon.social/@BorisBarbour"&gt;@&lt;span&gt;BorisBarbour&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; there are now preprints, see Nature explainer from Phil Ball &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-01992-0" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;nature.com/articles/d41586-023&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;-01992-0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110555880474857280</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 20:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stephanie M. Lee</title><link>https://sciencemastodon.com/@stephaniemlee/110556018811458607</link><description>SCOOP: You may recall that in 2021, a famous study about honesty got retracted due to fraudulent data (ironic).But that wasn't the end of the story. An author now tells me that per a Harvard investigation, the study had even more fraudulent data than previously revealed ... &lt;a href="https://www.chronicle.com/article/a-weird-research-misconduct-scandal-about-dishonesty-just-got-weirder" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;chronicle.com/article/a-weird-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;research-misconduct-scandal-about-dishonesty-just-got-weirder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110558745488592775</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 09:02:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>