<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Mastodon Home Timeline</title><link>https://mastodon.social</link><description>RSS feed for the Mastodon Home timeline</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 14:18:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Terence Tao</title><link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@tao/113873092369347147</link><description>The behavior of a high-dimensional dynamical system can, very roughly speaking, be divided into two regimes.  The first is what one might call the "effective dynamics" regime, in which the complex, high-dimensional dynamics can be well approximated (in the observables that one particularly cares about, at least) by lower-dimensional effective equations or models that emerge from the more fundamental laws of motion, and are easier to understand and analyze.  A classical example is the laws of thermodynamics, which can effectively govern (some of the) macroscopic behavior of a large number of interacting particles, due to mixing effects that greatly simplify the impact of most of the degrees of freedom.  Another example from physics is Hooke's law, that asserts that an elastic object, such as a spring, exerts a linear restoring force to push it in the direction of its equilibrium.  Similar linear restoring force phenomena can be seen across the sciences (such as climate science, biology, economics, or even political science): not as fundamental laws of nature, but as empirically observable laws that emerge from more fundamental ones. Such effective laws can provide a valuable amount of long-term stability, predictability, and simplification to the dynamical understanding of many real-world complex systems.  (1/4)</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113873188830312106</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 17:29:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Terence Tao</title><link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@tao/113873093136625989</link><description>In many cases, the effective dynamics essentially decouple many of the degrees of freedom, allowing one to study simpler subsystems almost in isolation, with only a few bulk variables remaining to represent all the exogenous factors.  (This is for instance the case in modern economics, in which a complex economy of a large number of independent agents can be decoupled, as an initial approximation, into independent microeconomic systems, interacting with some background macroeconomic variables such as inflation, interest rates, or unemployment.)However, there is also complementary regime of "no effective dynamics", where the hypotheses on the system state that permit simpler approximations to the dynamics to be effective break down (particularly over longer time scales), because some key variables become non-perturbative, or so correlated with other variables that statistical laws such as the law of large numbers are no longer accurate.  For instance, if one pulls a spring too far from its equilibrium, then the internal structure of the spring can be impacted, and the restoring force can become nonlinear, or cease to exist entirely (or in more plain language, the spring can break if pulled too hard). (2/4)</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113873188927599472</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 17:29:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Terence Tao</title><link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@tao/113873093906145183</link><description>In many aspects of the modern world (economic, political, environmental, technological, etc.), we are arguably transitioning from a predictable regime of effective dynamics to a more uncertain regime without such effective dynamics.  As such, empirical laws that were trustworthy in the past, may become significantly less accurate, and can in fact become dangerous to rely upon too blindly.  (An example from my own recent personal experience: as the world's climate departs from its historical equilibrium state, the empirical observation that dangerous fires mainly occur in summer rather than winter is no longer safe to assume.)  The world is becoming more non-perturbative, more nonlinear, and more coupled; developments in distant countries or demographics, or in distant disciplines, have more impact on one's personal life than before, in ways that cannot be easily described by a small number of macro variables.  (Example: the COVID-19 pandemic.) (3/4)</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113873189174340685</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 17:29:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Terence Tao</title><link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@tao/113873094911081488</link><description>Meanwhile, the trend in recent years has been to prefer models of the world that are as simplified or low dimensional as possible - in particular, short enough to describe in a meme, short text, or short video to circulate on social media.  For instance, regarding the Los Angeles fires, there were several comments on such media suggesting that one simply use the water from the nearby Pacific Ocean to douse the fires, suggesting an oversimplified firefighting model in which complex issues of logistics, wind, salt corrosion, etc. were reduced to the mere proximity of any large source of water, regardless of quality or supporting infrastructure.  As H. J. Mencken wrote back in 1920, "Explanations exist; they have existed for all time; there is always a well-known solution to every human problem—neat, plausible, and wrong."Complex dynamics are going to require complex solutions, in which simplified models are still partially used when appropriate, but with as much awareness of their limitations as possible; long-standing assumptions are tested and updated as new information about the current state of the world comes in; and human expertise and perspectives on the many different aspects of the problem are combined in a constructive fashion.  These are all achievable practices - indeed, in my own field of mathematics, they are all completely standard parts of our workflow.  Despite recent trends, I do hope that they will also be adopted more broadly. (4/4)</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113873189214945494</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 17:29:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earl K. Miller</title><link>https://fediscience.org/@ekmiller/113873364567474592</link><description>Electric fields influences propagate nearly instantaneously, enabling large-scale organization. This mechanism is critical for guiding morphogenesis.  Also for organizing thought.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s13752-020-00341-y" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;link.springer.com/article/10.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;007/s13752-020-00341-y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://fediscience.org/tags/neuroscience" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;neuroscience&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113873364769361109</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 18:14:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Glyn Moody</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@glynmoody/113872809799988948</link><description>&lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/Spain" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;Spain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;'s PM accuses tech billionaires of wanting to overthrow democracy - &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/live/2025/jan/22/davos-day-two-rachel-reeves-uk-economy-ai-un-europe-live-updates?page=with:block-679104318f08b977fd67e835#block-679104318f08b977fd67e835" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;theguardian.com/business/live/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;2025/jan/22/davos-day-two-rachel-reeves-uk-economy-ai-un-europe-live-updates?page=with:block-679104318f08b977fd67e835#block-679104318f08b977fd67e835&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; "Sanchez went on to argue that social media is a common resource for humanity, like the oceans, and they should be managed accordingly." &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/commons" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;commons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113873541777681489</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 18:59:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apollo Noir</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@apollonoir/113872919267077420</link><description>Si vous n’aviez pas encore compris&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/113/872/918/487/024/656/original/e51136d8bcb1f093.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/113/872/918/487/024/656/original/e51136d8bcb1f093.png" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113874186870765804</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 21:43:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Laffy</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@GottaLaff/113868995950593591</link><description>📣Whatever it takes to bring followers over to my new &lt;span class="h-card" translate="no"&gt;&lt;a class="u-url mention" href="https://mstdn.social/@GottaLaff"&gt;@&lt;span&gt;GottaLaff@mstdn.social&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; account, I've failed.So, please spread the word to my usual friends to follow me there if somehow I messed up that part of the move.I'm having a tough time getting it right. Sorry.📢</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113874213958819717</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 21:50:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Linux Is Best</title><link>https://misskey.de/notes/a3b41p8prp</link><description>&lt;a class="u-url mention" href="https://masto.nu/@estelle4565" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;@estelle4565@masto.nu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="u-url mention" href="https://infosec.exchange/@thenexusofprivacy" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;@thenexusofprivacy@infosec.exchange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;That actually happens everytime we have a new President and it was not forced.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;POTUS, short for, President of the United States, is the Presidental Account. It automatically gets assigned to whoever is President. If you followed, the POTUS account when it was Joe Biden, it simply converted to Donald Trump. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Facebook.com/POTUS is always whoever is President.&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113874241808908435</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 21:57:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Qasim Rashid, Esq.</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@QasimRashid/113874479669751953</link><description>Let’s be clear. Trump did not repel the EEOC. An executive order cannot repeal legislation. Trump revoked President Johnson’s Executive Order 11246, which protected affirmative action for federal contractors. Trump’s EO does not impact Title VII or laws enforced by the EEOC.&lt;br/&gt;He may try to do so via legislation. But this is not that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113874490660358064</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SellaTheChemist</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@sellathechemist/113874251015057720</link><description>Had a long chat with one of my personal tutees (students for whom I have pastoral care). Very smart, articulate, and funny young woman who is ASD and has a modest physical disability. She told me about an automated interview where the AI gave her some kind of feedback at the end. Apparently it "concluded" that she is not a team player and is anti-social. This could not be more wrong. I wonder whether she will get a rejection tomorrow…  I'm pretty outraged.  &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/AI" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;AI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/bias" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;bias&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/risk" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;risk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/disability" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;disability&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113874583320139609</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:24:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Weyoun 6</title><link>https://kolektiva.social/@weyoun6/113874456412622578</link><description>&lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://kolektiva.social/tags/USPol" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;USPol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Not satire.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/113/874/456/499/763/281/original/3f167ccf721ac62f.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/113/874/456/499/763/281/original/3f167ccf721ac62f.jpg" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113874623212331631</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:34:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gregor Kalinkat</title><link>https://det.social/@gkalinkat/113874623586497802</link><description>&lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://det.social/tags/Trump" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;Trump&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; hits NIH with ‘devastating’ freezes on meetings, travel, communications, and hiring &lt;a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/trump-hits-nih-devastating-freezes-meetings-travel-communications-and-hiring" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;science.org/content/article/tr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;ump-hits-nih-devastating-freezes-meetings-travel-communications-and-hiring&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://det.social/tags/science" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;science&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://det.social/tags/uspol" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;uspol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113874668904003386</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spencer LaVere Smith</title><link>https://neuromatch.social/@sls/113874847520431890</link><description>Mencken said that truly civilized people are "skeptical and tolerant".Rigor and compassion are often lacking in popular political discussions. The one thing that is needed even more urgently is leadership. Another Mencken quote: "It doesn’t take a majority to make a rebellion; it takes only a few determined leaders and a sound cause."&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://labrigger.com/blog/2025/01/22/5466/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;http://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;labrigger.com/blog/2025/01/22/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;5466/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113874847579691078</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:31:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Matt Blaze</title><link>https://federate.social/@mattblaze/113874970715601695</link><description>That the new administration is opposed to "DEI" (and is quick to use it as a scapegoat for just about everything bad) is unsurprising and was expected, but the aggressiveness of today's anti-DEI purge is still jarring and disturbing. They are creating an atmosphere in which any attempt to hire, promote, or engage with anyone other than a white male will be regarded as inherently suspect.The damage - to both individuals and to our institutions - will likely be both swift and long lasting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113876541108324081</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 07:41:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gabriele Svelto</title><link>https://fosstodon.org/@gabrielesvelto/113876795164492362</link><description>The whole "Roman salute" thing needs some clarification. There's no such thing as a "Roman salute". It was made up by fascists in Italy and then copied by the nazi regime. Only fascists use it. End of story.&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roman_salute" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roman_sa&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;lute&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/113/876/795/236/774/415/original/8b60399260225735.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/cache/media_attachments/files/113/876/795/236/774/415/original/8b60399260225735.png" alt="Mastodon image" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113877396814677525</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 11:19:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Simon Phipps</title><link>https://meshed.cloud/@webmink/113877383573705900</link><description>Will Trump cause the EU to declare use of US &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://meshed.cloud/tags/cloud" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;cloud&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; services illegal for &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://meshed.cloud/tags/privacy" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;privacy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reasons?&lt;a href="https://noyb.eu/en/us-cloud-soon-illegal-trump-punches-first-hole-eu-us-data-deal" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;noyb.eu/en/us-cloud-soon-illeg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;al-trump-punches-first-hole-eu-us-data-deal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113877417874875574</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 11:24:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Boris Barbour</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@BorisBarbour/113877495850984903</link><description>Maybe Wikipedia should build a search engine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113877495850984903</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 11:44:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nils Wilcke</title><link>https://mastodon.social/@paul_denton/113877318959923787</link><description>Dati prévoit de discuter avec le député RN Philippe Ballard qui fait le siège de son ministère pour empêcher un "droit d'agrément" des journalistes sur la nomination de leur directeur de rédaction, une disposition prévue par la proposition de loi écolo sur les médias. Sans surprise, le parti de Marine Le Pen joue pour Bolloré, visé par la proposition de loi écolo après son rachat du JDD et la nomination de Geoffroy Lejeune à la tête du journal. &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/Politique" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;Politique&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/Bollore" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;Bollore&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/RN" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;RN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/Dati" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;Dati&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/Medias" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;Medias&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://mastodon.social/tags/Presse" rel="tag"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;Presse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113877501045522661</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 11:46:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earl K. Miller</title><link>https://fediscience.org/@ekmiller/113877884692847189</link><description>Cognitive neuroscience: How the brain navigates abstract task spaces&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cell.com/current-biology/abstract/S0960-9822(24)01644-0" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" translate="no"&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ellipsis"&gt;cell.com/current-biology/abstr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="invisible"&gt;act/S0960-9822(24)01644-0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a class="mention hashtag" href="https://fediscience.org/tags/neuroscience" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#&lt;span&gt;neuroscience&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113877884940187605</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 13:23:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>